<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on xkyle.com</title>
    <link>/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on xkyle.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 02:04:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Balanced Payments Puzzle 1</title>
      <link>/decoding-balanced-payments-puzzle-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 02:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/decoding-balanced-payments-puzzle-1/</guid>
      <description>A strange string appeared at the bottom of a Balanced Payments blog post:
 NmQ2ZjYzMmU3Mzc0NmU2NTZkNzk2MTcwNjQ2NTYzNm U2MTZjNjE2MjQwNjU2MzZlNjU3MjY1NjY2NjY5NjQ2MTY1N mI2MTZkNmY3NDc0NmU2MTc3Njk=
 One of those puzzles to attract coders I guess. The guys at Hacker News spilled the beans, so lets spill them some more.
First though,** Mad Props** to the Balanced team for thinking &amp;ldquo;outside&amp;rdquo; the unit-test-box. Plus Jenkins rocks. The world needs more Jenkins. Bash? I&#39;m not a developer, so my first instinct was to use the existing set of tools that people have already written to solve this puzzle:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving &#34;Role Playing 4&#34;</title>
      <link>/solving-role-playing-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 20:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/solving-role-playing-4/</guid>
      <description>Last month Games Magazine published their Online Contest 29 - Role Playing 4. Here is the puzzle:

The circles represent actors, the diamonds represent movies they have been in. Pink is for actresses and blue is for actors. The numbers represent the numbers in their name: First, Last. Question marks indicate the number in their name is 3,4,6, or 9 letters. The center actress is what we are after. Note there are no clues for her name, but she has been in 13 movies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Assisted Jenga with the Wii Balance Board and Linux</title>
      <link>/computer-assisted-jenga-with-the-wii-balance-board-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 05:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-assisted-jenga-with-the-wii-balance-board-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>I like to think about how games work, in the case of Jenga, it is just physics!
But don&#39;t you wish you could peel back reality and see what is happening with the physics from the inside? Well now you can, with the help of a Wii Balance Board.

For the setup you need these ingredients:
  Wii Balance Board
  Computer with Bluetooth
  Linux, preferably Ubuntu</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>