<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on xkyle.com</title>
    <link>/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on xkyle.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 02:04:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Balanced Payments Puzzle 1</title>
      <link>/decoding-balanced-payments-puzzle-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 02:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/decoding-balanced-payments-puzzle-1/</guid>
      <description>A strange string appeared at the bottom of a Balanced Payments blog post:
NmQ2ZjYzMmU3Mzc0NmU2NTZkNzk2MTcwNjQ2NTYzNm U2MTZjNjE2MjQwNjU2MzZlNjU3MjY1NjY2NjY5NjQ2MTY1N mI2MTZkNmY3NDc0NmU2MTc3Njk=
One of those puzzles to attract coders I guess. The guys at Hacker News spilled the beans, so lets spill them some more.
First though,** Mad Props** to the Balanced team for thinking &amp;ldquo;outside&amp;rdquo; the unit-test-box. Plus Jenkins rocks. The world needs more Jenkins. Bash? I&amp;rsquo;m not a developer, so my first instinct was to use the existing set of tools that people have already written to solve this puzzle:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discrete Wavelets Final Project - Decaptcha,</title>
      <link>/discrete-wavelets-final-project-decaptcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 17:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/discrete-wavelets-final-project-decaptcha/</guid>
      <description>This semester I took a class on Discrete Wavelets. It was awesome. The coolest part was our group final project. My group had the best topic by far: Decoding a Captcha! (Click on any of the following images to view them full size)
We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen Captchas before. They are used on websites to make sure that the person on the website is a real human, not a computer program. Why do we want to break them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAP Solutions Hack</title>
      <link>/pap-solutions-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 17:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/pap-solutions-hack/</guid>
      <description>My girlfirend likes to do these puzzles called Pic-A-Pix from ConceptisPuzzles. They use a matrix of numbers to hint the puzzler to to filling in pixels to create pixel art. Sometimes there is color. Every week four new PAP&amp;rsquo;s are pushed out, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that the answers are somewhere on the website&amp;hellip;. but that would be cheating. :)
So I wrote my own program to decode these and make images using html tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Arp Alerts II!</title>
      <link>/custom-arp-alerts-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 11:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/custom-arp-alerts-ii/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve found a better way to do what I did in the previous post. Instead of running a separate script to parse the arp alert logs, I have arp alert itself send the alerts! The key is this line in the arpalert.conf
action on detect = &amp;quot;/etc/scripts/arp-alert&amp;quot; Its so simple, it just runs that script sending the information about the alert as certain arguments. With this I have more control over the formatting of arpalert messages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Arp-Alerts</title>
      <link>/custom-arp-alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 23:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/custom-arp-alerts/</guid>
      <description>So I was looking around, and I wanted some sort of tool to allow me to be more aware about what was happening in the lower &amp;ldquo;bowels&amp;rdquo; of the network that I&amp;rsquo;m on with my laptop. So what is it that I want&amp;hellip;
What I really want is some sort of mac-address based buddy list. One that would show my a list of the mac addresses talking on my network, and allow me to alias them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS Cache Poisoning </title>
      <link>/dns-cache-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/dns-cache-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>Recently a DNS expert found a flaw in the way that DNS servers talk to other DNS servers to get records that allows interested parties (hackers) to insert their own records. If you need a primer: the Wikipedia link.
Well&amp;hellip; a DNS flaw is no fun without a tool to use it. So this guy &amp;ldquo;HD Moore&amp;rdquo; wrote a program (script) that takes advantage of this and makes it relatively easy for someone to use something called Metasploit to tinker with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
