<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gun on xkyle.com</title>
    <link>/categories/gun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gun on xkyle.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2007 06:34:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/gun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Piece: Armband</title>
      <link>/next-piece-armband/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2007 06:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next-piece-armband/</guid>
      <description>We were thinking it would be cool to have the LCD display be on the arm, instead of the side of the gun.
So we have modified roller-blading wrist-guards for the purpose:

Watch Karl Show It Off!
Karl&#39;s Mom helped with the sewing. Next we&#39;ll add buttons for mode and backlight. I think they will be very thin and unobtrusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our First Real Gun</title>
      <link>/our-first-real-gun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 06:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/our-first-real-gun/</guid>
      <description>Here it is, the big milestone: our first real gun!
From this: 
To this!
You can see how we have gutted an air-soft gun, and inserted our led&#39;s and switches to turn it into a lasertag gun. All of our guns will be interchangeable as they will all have the same Cat-5 Pinout. Eventually we will have an array of guns and we can change their properties in software. (Reload times, shots per clip, damage per shot, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototype #1</title>
      <link>/prototype-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 15:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/prototype-1/</guid>
      <description>Here are some pictures and some short video of our first prototype gun!
A more or less finished backpack.
2x4 Gun and LCD wristbandI love having good tools, and this $40 soldering iron is the best $40 I ever spent.
Nicd battery pack! With velcro! 
And Kyle explains it all! Sort of&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasertag Camo</title>
      <link>/lasertag-camo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 23:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lasertag-camo/</guid>
      <description>Karl and I have taken our backpacks and spraypainted them camo! And we have installed a few components for two test boxes. (Radio, Mainboard, and ISD) 
You can see me wiring the usb port for the usb key thing. (It stores your personal stats)
More to come as we prototype our first two boxes!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>