<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openwrt on xkyle.com</title>
    <link>/categories/openwrt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openwrt on xkyle.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 01:45:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/openwrt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overdrive Pro Connecting on OpenWrt</title>
      <link>/an-overdrive-pro-connecting-on-openwrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 01:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/an-overdrive-pro-connecting-on-openwrt/</guid>
      <description>Have a fancy FreedomPop Overdrive Pro? Want to hook it up to your OpenWrt based router to use as a backup (or primary?) internet connection? Lets do it.
Plug it into your router via USB. Then run:
opkg install kmod-usb-net-cdc-ether  Run dmesg and it will report which eth device came up. Mine shows up as &amp;ldquo;eth1&amp;rdquo;. Now make eth1 your &amp;ldquo;wan&amp;rdquo; interface:
uci set network.wan.ifname=eth1 uci commit reboot  Whoa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Things to Do After Installing OpenWrt</title>
      <link>/cool-things-to-do-after-installing-openwrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 23:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cool-things-to-do-after-installing-openwrt/</guid>
      <description>OpenWrt is the bomb. Think all the power of a full Linux distro on your tiny home router or plug computer.
Install an External Root Overlay What the heck does that mean? OpenWrt uses an ingenious system were the root filesystem is a super compressed squashfs, merged with a read/write jffs2 filesystem called the overlay. This maximizes your available space on the device. Instead of using part of your remaining flash for read/write, you can use a larger, external device for the overlay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seagate Dockstar: A Very Cool Linux Device</title>
      <link>/the-seagate-dockstar-a-very-cool-linux-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 05:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-seagate-dockstar-a-very-cool-linux-device/</guid>
      <description>What if I told you there was a computer out there, a small one, with gigabit ethernet, 4 USB 2.0 ports, runs on 5 watts, and serves as a great NAS (network attached storage) for your home. It can share files, serve media, be a router, make backups for you, host a lamp stack, be a mail server, etc. It can do whatever you can think up.

How much would you pay for such a neat little device?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving My WRT54GL a 2G Drive</title>
      <link>/giving-my-wrt54gl-a-2g-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 22:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/giving-my-wrt54gl-a-2g-drive/</guid>
      <description>The WRT54GL is a pretty cool little toy. Yes it is a router with a cheezy web interface for grandmas with ESSID&amp;rsquo;s named &amp;ldquo;linksys&amp;rdquo;. But you can flash it with your own linux and solder in your own SD card to turn it from a 4MB machine to a 2GB machine&amp;hellip; far out!

Above it the bare board that I&amp;rsquo;ve unscrewed out of the thing. Some solder + a card&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>