<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sensu on xkyle.com</title>
    <link>/categories/sensu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sensu on xkyle.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 18:21:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/sensu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Configuration Management Rosetta Stone: Configuring Sensu with Puppet, Chef, Ansible and Salt</title>
      <link>/configuration-management-rosetta-stone-configuring-sensu-with-puppet-chef-ansible-and-salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 18:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/configuration-management-rosetta-stone-configuring-sensu-with-puppet-chef-ansible-and-salt/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished my Intermediate Sensu Training on Udemy. It was a ton of work but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got it all together. Part of that training includes how to deploy and configure Sensu with four of the most popular open-source configuration management tools: Puppet, Chef, Ansible, and Salt.
 TOC {:toc}  The Sensu Decree In order to do the training I had to learn each of these tools enough so I could install a baseline Sensu installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing sensu-shell-helper!</title>
      <link>/Introducing-sensu-shell-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 09:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/Introducing-sensu-shell-helper/</guid>
      <description>The Problem The barrier to writing Nagios checks is high. I dare say very high. You have to think about check intervals, host groups, service groups, config files, etc.
But, I know my servers are not behaving, if only there was a way to check them! They run commands for me all the time. In the worst case they fail and no one knows. The best case is that they end up in my cron spam folder&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensu Reports in your Motd with Puppet!</title>
      <link>/sensu-reports-in-your-motd-with-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sensu-reports-in-your-motd-with-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Intro Sensu is a pretty cool monitoring framework. The authors designed it to be configured by a configuration management system from the beginning. Check out how easily I can make it put a report in my motd with a little bit of python and puppet.
The Report Script Sensu&amp;rsquo;s API is super easy to work with. For this I will be using the Events endpoint. Here is a quick script to get the events for a host (gist):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Sensu Using Puppet. For Real. </title>
      <link>/getting-started-with-sensu-using-puppet-for-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 01:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/getting-started-with-sensu-using-puppet-for-real/</guid>
      <description>Nagios. So familiar. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve run Nagios at every job I have ever had.
Talk to most ops people, even at really big places, and they will probably admit to using it.
Puppet&amp;rsquo;s exported resources takes away some of the pain, but sometimes I think to myself, there must be a better way to do this. Sensu might be that better way.
Let&amp;rsquo;s try it out, but gosh, I am SO lazy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
